ladies and gentlemen good day and
welcome to the Q2 results investor
conference call of tber India
limited as a reminder all participant
lines will be in the listen only mode
and there will be an opportunity for you
to ask questions after the presentation
concludes should you need assistance
during the conference call please signal
an operator by pressing star then zero
on your Touchstone
phone please note that the conference is
being
recorded I now hand the conference over
to miss gagan alalia thank you and over
to you thank you Stanford good afternoon
ladies and gentlemen on behalf of the
management of D India limited I welcome
you to this conference call pertaining
to results for the quarter end of 30th
September
2020 I have here with me Mr Mohit motra
chief executive officer D India limited
Mr lit Malik Chief Financial Officer off
Mr ashoke Jen senior vice president
finance and Company secretary and Mr
anush Jen head Financial Planning and
Analysis we will now start with an
overview of the company's performance by
Mr motra followed by a Q&A session I now
request Mr M motra to start the
presentation thank
you thank you again Madam good afternoon
ladies and gentlemen I hope all of you
and your families are staying safe and
healthy during these tough times let me
also wish you a very happy Diwali to all
of you and a great festive season
ahead our war against covid is not yet
over and my heart goes out to all those
who have been affected by the virus I
would like to express my deepest
gratitude to the Frontline Corona
Warriors our police Personnel healthcare
workers and sanitization workers for
their selfless service towards keeping
us all safe during these trying times
moments of extraordinary challenge like
these test our Collective will and I'm
proud and inspired by the way the entire
extended daa family from factories to
supply chain to the Frontline Salesforce
have risen to this challenge across the
globe I would like to thank them for
their hard work commitment and
invaluable contributions which have
helped us whether the covid storm and
emerg even stronger they are our true
heroes
Co has entirely changed the business
landscape around the globe opening up
newer categories and challenges while
dismantling some of the established ones
as I've often said a crisis is not to be
wasted it is in fact an opportunity to
work harder strengthen the business with
new capabilities beliefs and Innovations
to emerge stronger and even further
entrench our leadership position in the
marketplace this is exactly what we did
in covid times we have transformed
ourselves as an organization becoming
more agile Nimble aggressive and
fearless we have also enhanced our
risk-taking ability encouraging our
employees to become more entrepreneurial
and self- driven this crisis has
propelled the company towards the
journey wherein we have accelerated the
pace of innovation retooled our
distribution increased digitization
across value chain enhanced our
efficiency and productivity and brought
in a complete cultural change within the
company we have launched multiple new
products since the Advent of Co in spite
of restrictions on supply chain and
limited availability of Labor and raw
materials I can say that this has been
the inflection point for the company
which has brought in enduring changes in
the way we operate our strategic
business transformation exercise helped
us to develop and Implement growth
strategies in the core business areas to
successfully address the emerging
challenges and deliver a robust Topline
growth accompanied by healthy
profitability during the quarter we saw
a growth of 13.7% in Consolidated
revenue from operations our fmcg
business recorded a stellar growth of
20% backed by a volume growth of
16.8% operating profit increased by
16.3% and Consolidated profit after tax
reported a growth of 19.5%
riding the Tailwind of immunity products
and bolstered with the new Innovative
launches the healthcare portfolio
recorded a growth of around 50% this was
driven by a strong growth in our power
Brands and Healthcare portfolio and
supported by Creative Marketing
campaigns localized sales activations
and sustained Investments the health
supplement business grew by 70% led by
2x surge in sales of Chan prash a double
digigit growth in Honey OTC bu has
reported a strong growth of 56% on back
of robust performance of lale and the
npds like heal juices heal strops and
other ayurvedic products the ethical
business also performed well reported a
growth of
26% on back of strong demand for
immunity boosting products contextual
activations visibility drives in chemist
channels and initiatives like immunity
at
doorstep within HPC portfolio Oral Care
recorded a industry leading growth of
24.2% dber red space our Flagship brand
continued its growth momentum along with
a strong performance of miswar and babou
franchise a market share in toothpaste
category witnessed a 90 basis point gain
Vis last year our L dant manin also
witnessed a strong growth of 30% during
the quarter her oils reported a marginal
decline primarily on account of lower
sales in the Enterprise business
particularly CSD business which
continues to be impacted X Enterprise
the sales of hair oils was flattish our
flanker brand strategy remains intact
with the launch of badam amla and amla
aloe
vera the shampoo portfolio recorded a
growth of
17.8% our market share in shampoo
business increased by 80 basis points
touching
6.4% our focus on increasing bottle
salience in yielding results has yielded
results with a strong surge seen in the
quarter vatia shampoo reported a good
off take on e-commerce platform as well
Home Care reported a muted performance
during the quarter due to discretionary
nature of this portfolio the air
fresheners and mosquito repellent
screams were under some pressure however
our market shares in both the categories
saw an uptick in air freshness odonil
recorded an increase of 60 basis point
in market share and in mosquito
repellent cream category odos recorded a
Improvement of 80 basis points the
recently launched home hygiene portfolio
under dber sanitized and dber dazzled
brands have registered a strong
performance skare portfolio witnessed a
growth of 38% driven by strong
performance of dber sanitize range which
includes hand sanitizers antiseptic
liquids and soaps along with f
handwashes
portfolio I'll beat the traditional
portfolio of HRC bleaches declined by
around
12% with the hka and CSD businesses
continuing to operate at lower levels
the food business reported a decline of
3.8% X hka and CSD the domestic Foods
business saw a growth of
8.5% the inhome domestic business has
sharply rebound while the out of home
portfolio has seen sequential recovery
month on month our market share in jnn
category saw an increase of 170 basis
points reaching to a market share of
61.5% our culinary portfolio under the
homemade brand recorded a growth of 12%
domestic business for culinary X hka and
CSD has shown a strong growth of
45% the new products launched under the
foods portfolio were real mango drink
real frappe milkshakes who which are
also witnessing encouraging response
from the
market among the channels e-commerce was
an outperformer with a growth of more
than 200% this channel is now
contributing to around 6% of sales Vis
2% last year we were able to capture the
increasing preference for online
purchases among the consumers and
increase our market shares on e-commerce
platforms across categories
international business recorded a muted
growth of 5.5 during the quarter while
Mina region continues to face
macroeconomic headwinds due to lower
crude prices and outward movement of
exps we strong we saw strong double
digigit growth in Turkey North America
and Fark businesses new products were
launched in hair care skin care hygiene
categories the business reported an
increase in operating margins aided by
Saving initiatives across the board We
Believe Innovation is a corner
Cornerstone of our strategy to deliver
robust growth and tap the emerging
opportunities during the quarter we
extended our portfolio with the launch
of darber Honey immunity range Tulsi and
ashwagandha variants dber herbal clove
toothpaste in South amla aloe vera hair
oil dber badam amla hair oil low calorie
juices and real Apple mini we also
entered new categories with launch of
single herbs dvic suraka tea ayurvedic
nasal drops along with chutne Pickles
range in The Culinary portfolio
e-commerce continues to be a driver of
growth and we fortified it with the
recent Ecom first brand launches of dber
him Himalayan apple cider vinegar baby
range and cold FES mustard oil going
forward we we intend to drive our
business by investing aggressively
behind Our Brands staying focused on
health and hygiene driving Innovation
and renovation across our portfolio
leveraging the new way channels like
e-commerce Cash and Carry and modern
trade besides expanding and enhancing
the efficiency of a distribution Network
these initiatives are coupled with cost
and cash flow management to ensure
stable and healthy margins I would once
again take this opportunity to
acknowledge the superlative efforts of
each and every member of the dber family
from our plants to the sales
organization who have gone above and
beyond the Call of Duty to catalyze the
transformation of dber into a stronger
more Nimble and agile
Enterprise while the challenge of covid
Still Remains we will strive to continue
our Pursuit for excellence and stay
course on our strategy of strengthening
and daging our power Brands expanding
distribution footprint digitization
across the Val chain in the company cost
optimization and building organizational
capabilities for sustainable and
profitable future growth with this I
will now open the Q&A and invite your
questions thank you thank you very much
sir ladies and gentlemen we will now
begin the question and answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
please press T then one on their
Touchstone
telephone if you wish to remove yourself
from the question Q you may press St
then too participants are requested to
use handsets while asking a
question anyone who wishes to ask
questions please press St then
one the first question is from the line
of of Nish Roy from need wice please go
ahead yeah M congrats on very good set
of numbers so my first question is on
the Oral Care portfolio so two questions
one uh market share data other companies
are seeing is not reliable because of
the lockdown so if you could comment on
that second uh how much is the
contribution of dakak and the club dber
club in the uh percentage of sales this
this
quarter yeah to me market sh uh thank
you Amish first of all I think um thanks
for your support So market share data
actually in my mind is pretty robust and
it's very indicative of the way we've
actually performed so Oral Care uh
Market shows a uptick of around 5% and
as compared to 5% dber shares in N are
showing a growth of almost like around
uh 10% for us in the newon data whereas
our business in terms of our secondary
in primary is showing a growth of around
24% so in my mind it's pretty indicative
and the difference between our sales and
the newon saves remains intact that said
there were Co disturbances which n also
witnessed in their field work while they
were collecting the data but uh overall
it seems to be in line with the
performance that we've shown uh so
that's on that as far as dakak and dber
clo are concerned having very minuscule
performance we guys just rolled out
these Brands around two months back
still there is pipeline filling
happening overall we would have only
done around 7even or crores out of dakak
and uh very small one or two crores out
of cloves which is uh insignificant to
our overall performance of Oral
Care uh my second question is on the new
products and very high ENT spend so if I
see sanitizer ACV and herbal te uh these
are not products in which you have a
right to win because you have entered
here late already established players
are there so one will you advertise here
and second will this go into the general
trade also at some point of time
right as far as sanitizer is concerned
at n we've actually tried to create a
vertical of home and hygiene under the
brand called sanitize and this will
continue across our portfolio whether
it's a sanitizer it's a heart Surface
Cleaner or it's a home hygiene products
like antiseptic liquid soap Etc this is
a portfolio that we are trying to create
which is all about sanitization in my
view consumer habits are changing and
consumer behavior of purchase is also
changing and these habits will ingrain
as we go going forward and the number of
players in the market are very few and
far between here with the rets being one
of the player and one more one two more
players in this category rest of the
soap Market if you see is all about
beauty space and less about antiseptic
space to me uh Market is underfed in the
antiseptic space so there is a need of
multiple players as far as right to win
is concerned dber stands for health and
wellness and I feel we have a right to
win in these categories with a
credibility and Legacy of darber and the
trust given on our back so there is a
complete credibility of darber and a
right to win to uh get into these
categories if you see our antiseptic
liquids are doing fairly well and they
are not just plain chain antiseptic Le
they are herbal antiseptic liquids which
will actually carve their own niche in
the antiseptic liquid category the way
we guys did it in shampoos or the way we
guys have done it on Oral Care likewise
there are examples replete which I can
tell you one after the other wherein D
is carved out a niche of herbal and
natural in these more cosmetic or these
artificial category as far as apple
cider vinegar is concerned on e-commerce
it is showing very good traction there
are limited number of Brands present and
with the dver name we have a right to
win so your point is right we will be
extending this brand to Modern trade
also going forward as we launch
extensions and variants in apple cider
vinegar and have you seen a sales
slowdown in sanitizer
uh in terms of weekly sales
num yeah sanitizer sales have really
gone down there are multiple players who
entered into the market and uh uh the
prices have also come down the margins
have also reduced and everybody is
getting into a market be a larger
multinational or be The Local Company
there multiple players gone into the
market so therefore uh and the sales our
sales have also gone down we had
registered a total sales of around 80
odd crores in the first quarter and in
this quarter we've only registered
around 12 12 CR sales coming from
sanitizer business so it is not a
sustainable business it will go down
over a period of time and that's what we
had anticipated when we had launched it
was very contextual for the covid times
and uh that's what it served its purpose
and now the business will kind of mute
and we are pretty well prepared for that
but that said that was only one of the
products under the daa sanitized brand
but now we have got a multiple portfolio
under the sanitized brand which with the
new launches will tried more than up in
terms of margins and also turnovers in
the sanitized
portfolio right my last question is on
Chan crash 2x sales and strong growth in
the honey so any sense on how much
growth is coming from new customer
second uh is this all in-house uh
manufacturing third edible oil companies
are coming into this space uh do you see
a threat long-term in terms of market
share or because you have the dominant
share it will be a loss uh other players
uh if at
all yeah first of all DCP if you look at
the total penetration levels of uh chaan
pra chaan pra sits at a 2% penetration
level in the country only so the
penetration levels have gone up from 2%
to around 3 and a half 4% in the season
it will go up Beyond this also but that
said 4% is also very low as if you
compare with the herir oil portfolio you
are 90% penetration BCP is only around 2
3% penetration levels if I have to
compare myself with other developed
countries which is where India will move
from developing to a developed in other
developed countries like the US Health
supplements and nucal penetration levels
are 80% with the VMS contributing 80% in
India it's barely 10% level so the head
room for growth is huge so it's the
owners on companies like us to bring
about Sash and modern formats imp
palatable formats and better packaging
which can reverse the distribution uh
and then sky is the limit for increasing
the penetration back of chavan Crash we
think we should be able to increase the
penetration levels of neutral in the
country also uh going forward as far as
honey is concerned also honey
penetration levels are high so they are
in the range of around 24 25% and
they've gone up postco and uh multiple
players will come into the category but
if you look at other countries honey
penetrations are again the of around 60
70 so we have a huge Headroom to cover
as far as again honey potential is
concerned and more the number of
competitors come in the more uh share of
voice on media the more category expands
and therefore more players will come in
so more players are welcome into the
honey category while we try to protect
our T but they are welcome and we will
try to do our best in the marketplace to
uh fight
competition m one small followup there
so in ter of penetration for Chan
what are you doing on Lup so we have
seen hlex and comp come out with much
stronger much lower pricing smaller
packs so what are you doing there and
Manufacturing capacity if you could
discuss for chant is it all in
out yeah uh I'll answer the second
question first of n our manufacturing
capacities are all inous it's a very
sensitive product not everybody can make
it and if other companies claim to be
making it in third party I think one has
to be very sure that it's a propri
formulation which is registered or
author authorized or authenticated by
Ministry of aush before you buy because
Chan is a classical name and you need to
follow a classical proprietary
methodology of making the product Health
product before you say just taking it
from a third party and rolling it in the
market can be very risky for the health
of the consumer so that's why most of
them are not nuring it as chavan prash
they call it chavan AMU or they call it
chavan something etc etc so a Twist in
the tail which I think the consumer will
understand very fast for as far as we
are concerned it's all inhouse
manufacturing and which is very
proprietary to us and which is inspected
by uh Ministry of aush which is made as
per the text and we have augmented the
capacity our capacities were running
short we've augmented the capacity and
therefore we are expanding our capacity
we are actually taking a a mega project
in mp of roughly around 40 acres of land
we've also paid an advance for that and
we'll be commencing a production in
couple of months almost 3 months time so
we are augmenting the capacity of chavan
prash manufacturing going forward as
well now coming to talk about
penetration of chaan Pras and
introduction of lups yes we understand
there's a huge potential there and we
have to reduce the price points to make
it accessible to the rural consumer for
that it's early days yet but we are
working on some formats which are
amenable to lups and uh reducing the
price points there so we are working uh
on that it's difficult for me to uh let
you know at the moment sure thanks
that's all for me all the best thank you
thank you so
much thank you the next question is from
the line of pery panaki from IFL please
go
ahead uh hi moit and team congrats on a
very good set of numbers
uh my first question is uh on uh your
margins and uh related to ad spends also
in that context uh you've grown your ad
spends by 40% uh this quarter and uh
that has prevented the margins from
expanding so just wanted to know your
view on a sort of four to six quarter
basis uh where do you see ad spends uh
stabilizing and do you think that there
is any upside in your Abida margins from
these
levels right thanks pery uh so as far as
our ad spends are concerned I think if
you compare dber to other companies in
terms of the ad spends we are sitting uh
at a very low ad spend to revenue ratio
at the moment I think we have a lot of
catching up for us to do so we still sit
at around 8% ad spend ratio if I look at
the best-in-class companies who would be
spending still 12 % on above the line to
generate demand so there's a catching up
to do so therefore we'll have a leverage
coming in from other line items of cost
and also some somei project and they
will be invested behind uh on ad spend
and increasing our ad spends going
forward so for the balance of the year
we will only increase our ad spends V be
last year that's on ad spend and we
don't want to increase our margins we
want to keep the margins where they are
and we want to invest the upside or The
Leverage in the business into the ad
spend that's as far as the ad spend is
concerned now coming to the margins
we've already got upside on the
operating margins in India the operating
margins gone up by 22 basis points and
uh in Consolidated is around 50 basis
points that will happen and that's
already happened even in first half
you've seen a margin growth and in the
balance of the year we want to keep the
margins same as what they are to last
year so overall uh for the financial
year there will be an upside uh in the
margin of the first half getting
captured into the Balan part of the year
but uh Mo how do you look at the margins
on a slightly longer term basis let's
say on a 3 to four year basis uh do you
think that your margins which are let's
say at 21
22% they can like structurally go up to
25 27% I mean most of your
categories can actually do much higher
margins than that and of course the
foods margins are pulling that down I
understand that but your categories are
such that not too many products have
direct
comparables so from that point of view
they Niche products so to say so can the
margins not be higher on a 3 to five
year
perspective uh per you embarked on a
journey of innovation and launching npds
and now trying to get into categories
are much larger than where we are
already existing in because Co taught us
a lesson that we don't have to restrict
ourselves to discretionary categories a
high margin we also have to Pivot our
business to categories are larger and uh
which will give us the scale leverage so
therefore we have to invest the upsides
into advertising and like I told you
there's a uh Improvement required in our
advertising so in terms of long-term 2
to three years Horizon we are wanting to
invest in advertising and not increase
the margins to a level of 25% we're
doing it's more maintenance of margins
and little bit upside if it happens it
happens right so my second question is
uh on uh the growth of the healthcare
business uh right now that business is
doing very well of course there are
covid Tailwinds but uh once uh this kind
of growth anniversar ises uh how do we
look at uh growth going ahead uh do we
say that on the back of this 40 50% kind
of growth uh the growth uh in fi 22 uh
will be sort of low single digit or even
negative in those categories because the
base is just too high or do we say that
this is a new normal base and on that
base we will now have a normal
growth yeah so you know I can't give you
a very straight answer on that I don't
know as to uh how the business will
Trend I can only tell you the trends
going through forward I cannot forecast
what's going to happen next year but uh
I as I told you when I answered to abnes
that the penetration levels of
healthcare are going up in the country
and we are saying these penetration we
are seeing it happen like and multiple
players are coming in and therefore the
categories will expand as the categories
expand the market leader only gets to
capitalize from this kind of a tail wind
which will continue now in terms of
absolute growth rate whether we'll be
able to sustain answer may be no because
it'll come off a very high base now if
you look at chavan prash in last quarter
there was a low base and uh in the
coming quarter it's a winter quarter now
we've lapped over the high base of last
year of winter because Summer was
offseason in off season on low base we
had a high growth of 2x 3x as we enter
into the new quarter now have come off a
high base but still I'm seeing a growth
because the number of consumers are
actually going up who are using Chan
frash so there they are new customers
and when the new customers come in
that's a Delta growth which happens
although your base is higher so
therefore the overall category and the P
increases and the market leader with 60%
odd share which is us will only expand
so but exact quantification of the
number I'll not be able to do but I feel
the habits have got ingrained
prophylactic Health Care has become more
Salient it's got ingrained in the
consumer's buying Behavior so therefore
health and Hy is not going to disappear
from the country even in f522 so I will
not say that it will be a low single
digit or negative sort of a growth rate
in the category and we are doing uh and
it's just not the base or uh what the
market does it is also what you do to
yourself to take the business forward so
therefore we are cognizant of the fact
that there will be a high base and we
are planning for that and therefore
maybe more better formats will come in
more npds will come in we'll get into
better categories so I have we have full
12 months to actually work on the same
and we shall work to prove you wrong
that will be less than uh bit single
digit right M ma may I be permitted to
ask one small sub question on Chan prash
please please please so if you can just
tell me uh what was the household
penetration of your brand in Chan prash
uh uh in the season last year so that
would be Q3 last year uh versus what is
the household penetration today is it
higher than the Q3 of last year yeah
definitely it's higher by at least a
percentage point and we've seen it from
first quarter to now the third quarter
also as the enter into the season it's
gone up from 2 percentage to three and a
half percentage points and penetrations
have gone up and uh I still don't have
the data as yet but around 1 percentage
Point increase in penetrations have
happened but that sh is still very low
in the range of around 3
4% okay okay that that's it from me Mo
thanks and yeah thank you thank you ver
thank you the next question is from the
line of laka chra from JP Morgan please
go
ahead hi moit and team congratulations
on a strong print uh my first question
was on the foods business uh we saw 6%
growth excluding the Enterprise business
uh is it right to assume assume that
this quarter won't have the benefit of
any festive related loading and we
should see the full contribution of
testive only in Q3 and on some of the
new launches here like low cal juice
frappe um you have launched ipel variant
at 10 bucks what kind of distribution
these new launches have and uh how do
you think the contribution of these new
products will be in the overall sales
mix and if I could just check do you
think now this business is geared to
move to about double digit C
growth right as far as beverage business
concern you're absolutely right laa
beverage business X of hura X
institutional Enterprise business is
growing at 6 and a half% if you look at
the food business ex hka is growing at
8.5% for us and driven by culinary
portfolio and culinary is a homemade
homemade if you see the culinary
portfolio is growing at 12% % but if I
exclude hka culinary is growing at 45%
for us there is a Tailwind all the
culinary inh home consumption that we
see so that's uh so I think the food
business is back on recovery path very
strongly in beverage business there are
two sub segments of Beverage one is a
inhome and uh versus out of home if you
look at out of home also there's a
sequential recovery and out of home
which contributes around 35 40% of the
total business is growing at 3 and a
half% which whereas the category is
declining by around 34% so that is on
growth path the in home consumption is
growing by around 12% 11 and a half to
12% which is significant around 60 70%
of our portfolio which is a one lit pack
that has staged a recovery of around 11%
growth now although offseason but then
the growth is happening and I'm sure
this growth will continue going forward
uh in the you know first quarter next
year also when we come to the season
because people are shifting from
carbonated beverages to more healthy
drinks and juices are considered healthy
and carbonated beverage is a big Market
of 25,000 crores as here we talking
about only including drinks 6,000 to
7,500 CR market so there is a source of
business and people are moving from that
source of business here so I have no
doubt that juices will Trend back to uh
uh growth trajectory today is minus 35
but the growth will happen and if he
gain share we should get back to a
double digit on back of all these npds
of getting into the drinks market and
frae and local and restaging of brand
Etc so I don't think there's any doubt
that we'll get into a double digit
growth rate going forward in the uh
season next year uh NPD contributions
will be around 5 6% on the beverage
business we have a lot of potential
there in terms of we hardly scratching
the surface and utilizing the equity of
real real has a huge Market equity and
we will keep expanding that as far as
distribution is concerned we are very
small with NPD so NPD distribution is
going on seeding operations are
happening as yet and as we scale the
business we'll have to embark on new
distribution Network our existing
distribution Foods network is not end
Outlets are not doing Justice to the
drinks Market but as we scale up the
business we'll get on to more fat
dealers and more network of the drinks
space and that's where we'll be able to
grow the business as far as our separate
infrastructure of distribution is
concerned we are putting in more feet on
streets and more ssms and today we've
got a separate distribution Network in
metros and only in North India gradually
slowly we are expanding that also and
we'll have exclusive distribution
Network across India as we scale up the
new
businesses sure um if I could check a
little bit more on toothpaste uh could
you state the toothpaste growth in the
quarter I probably missed it and what is
really driving this this uh is it also
supported by some kind of Channel
inventory normalization is there a big
difference between the primary and
secondary opt here and
also are you happy with the traction for
dunure right as far as the Oral Care
categor is concerned um overal care
category if you see is growing by around
5% and E shows our growth at around 10%
if you look at the overall category is
growing by 5% the natural based
toothpaste category is trending at
around 8% so natural toothpaste segment
which is around 27 to 30% of the market
is growing at 8% overall Market is 5%
that means the chemical based toothpaste
or calcium carbonate Bas are actually uh
doing much worse as compared to the
Natural segment and the beneficiaries of
this growth are pangali as zoo and other
natural players so this natural sub
segment of Oral Care is actually growing
and this is growing across different
benefit segment also today it's limited
to anti cavity but tomorrow there will
be more benefit sub segmentations also
being carved out here in natural as the
segment becomes more and more attractive
and therefore you see for us all the
entire portfolio of Oral Care has done
well so we've revamped miswak and and
we've revamped it we've revamped bab
toothpaste and on back of bab aurvedic
bab franchise is doing well miswak is
doing well for us dber herbal toothpaste
which is limited to Kerala we gradually
slowly expanding it Beyond Kerala to
south of India therefore we've launched
clove toothpaste as one of the variants
uh uh there that's doing that's initial
early days yet but it's a NPD Daka has
been launched in areas where D red is
not very strong which is the northwest
where dber has a lot of equity because
pangali is a player which is very
Salient there and it's coming at a price
point of around 40 rupees per 100 G as
compared to d red which sits at 50
rupees we've got The Sweet Spot of price
point which is very attractive I think
it should gain strength there we've got
a turnover of around 6 seven crores yet
but that's small uh but I think the
initial feedback from the market is
around 20 to 30% repeat which is good by
any standpoint so I think we will
continue to push this brand and initial
feedback is pretty positive and we are
very hopeful on
danta sure uh thank you so much yeah as
far as I think I missed out primary and
secondary we have actually corrected our
pipelines by almost 9 days so and uh
overall and including Oral Care for us
so there's no pipeline loading which is
actually happened there's a pipeline
correction happened and 24% growth in
primary is also a 25% growth in
secondary so we've actually corrected
the pipeline so secondaries are higher
as compared to
primary uh that's that's very useful
thanks moit and all the best yeah thank
you L thank you the next question is
from the line of Prasad deshmuk from
Bank of America please go ahead hey hi
uh hi moit and team congratulations on
theq results so two questions for me uh
one is of the raw material exposure that
you guys have how much is linked to
Agriculture and uh do you have any
opinion on how the new reforms agre
reforms will impact these
costs right so Prasad our results are
very close to what you had estimated
closest to what you had estimated in
terms of uh results so I think you
predicted it very well I don't know how
you predicted it because we could also
not predicted but you predicted it and
we were startled when we saw your
estimates very closer to us but that
that aside on raw material exposure yes
um we have three buckets of raw
materials here one is petroleum and crud
linked and one is uh agre link and third
is speciality chemical and fourth is
juices portfolio so we have around uh uh
50% almost purchase happening on herbs
spices agriculture linked Commodities
even more than that so that is uh seeing
uh significant inflation going forward
and we are contemplating judicious price
increases in selective Subs segments and
uh to see how we can mitigate that
inflationary Trend which we are seeing
as far as quarter one quarter 2 was
concerned we saw deflationary trend on
back of crude and also on uh agriculture
but with msps and government reforms
coming in and which is more linked to
agre only we are seeing inflation
hitting us CPI is already sitting at 7%
plus and even WPI is seeing a growth of
around 2% so that we looking at how to
offset it by way of price increases so
are there any are there any efforts in
terms of getting into you know contract
forming or uh uh you know bypassing the
apmc completely so that cost structure
reduces
permanently we are evaluating we made a
cross functional team procurement and we
are seeing that in selective raw
materials we can actually go to large
scale Farmers to bypass the apmc but at
the moment uh not really because still
it's a very new act and uh we have not
come across you know suppliers with whom
we can engage directly so at the moment
We are continuing with both the apmc but
that said we' made a core committee and
they are still thinking and evaluating
the major raw materials in in which we
can go directly there
got it uh and the second question is on
your new launches in food these are
these look like mostly in ready to eat
or cooking Essentials uh so is it that
uh you know could you throw some light
on how you are selecting these
categories so especially something like
you know mustard oil is not is not
something that one could have expected
otherwise uh so how are you selecting
these categories and how do you plan to
scale up uh these products in term of in
terms of distribution
right so we are looking at opportunities
which are existing in the foods business
which are high business volume wherever
we have the right to win where
competitive intensity is low and where
the margins are actually higher so
there's a three way framework that we
evaluate every category that the scale
of business should be high competitive
intensity should be low our margin
should be high and we should have a
right to win so if all these three four
criterias are actually met that's when
we look at a uh category and then we
look at selective channels that do we
only get into e-commerce and if
e-commerce is a cradle of innovation or
cradle of where we can test Market our
brand if successful then we extend it to
Modern trade and then subsequently to GT
so we will do a proof of concept check
on e-commerce and if it does well then
we extend it so it's almost like a test
pilot that you do when we launch it on
e-commerce so you saw mustard oil is
only available on e-commerce yet Apple
CER vinegar only available on E Comm
Merce baby range only available in
e-commerce amla kids was only a
e-commerce launch so that's what now you
got a test marketing platform available
to yourself so therefore there's no uh
you know flip side of getting the stocks
back from the marketplace and Amazon and
other platforms also help you co-create
them and uh they are very keen to stock
all the innovations that you may have
got it so uh that's it from my side M
and many thanks for your kind words
thanks
thank you thank you very much yeah thank
you the next question is from the line
of arnab Metra from Credit Service
please go ahead uh yeah hi moit
congratulations on a brilliant quarter
uh my first question was on the NPD uh
uh npds from your side so uh if you
could uh you know help us uh in in terms
of the top five six npds which you would
say uh you've seen very good Traction in
and uh where you see scalability to
let's say a minimum threshold of 00 cres
of turnover over a few years uh wherever
you've seen uh strong traction and you
moved from e-commerce to General trade
uh and and you're seeing the roll out
continuing
there right so in terms of NPD if you
ask me our first 5 six will be pet
bottle is a very big one so Real's entry
into the drinks Market with pet bottle
so I think that's doing significantly
well second is our health drops are
doing pretty well then third is Health
juices are doing uh reasonably well then
um our amla plus juice is doing um good
uh good business pickles and Chutney
early days yet but I think that's doing
well apple cider vinegar uh I would find
that that's got established uh uh so
that's the big ones which I should say
are doing reasonably well so we've not
really entered into very very big
categories while it may seem that dber
has gone into a lot of NPD but we've
chosen our Battlegrounds very carefully
and um and wherever we've gone into
bigger categories there we've been very
Channel focused and got into for example
our Vic suraa te we've gone into te
category but that's more of a Cara
variant of a premium tea which is a junk
to daber where we have a right to win is
what we've launched it's almost like a
you know te replacement uh by Kaa so I
think those are the big ones and where
the competitive intensity will you will
see that it's low margins are pretty
high for us and um uh we have a right to
win here where D daa brand lends its
credibility to
us okay thanks thanks M for that and the
second question was uh you know when we
started this quarter at that time I
think growth in dber had come back to a
high single digit kind of territory and
you ended the at high team so obviously
you've gained some momentum through the
quarter while one would have assumed
possibly that with the reopening of the
economy covid uh the fear kind of
slightly going down the traction in some
of the categories uh may start tapering
off so have you not seen any tapering
off in terms of the broader Trends on
things like chaan prash which are very
immunity driven and actually would you
say that the the the the business is
continuing to grow very well because the
absolute distribution profile of the
category has changed quite a lot uh and
uh despite the covid fear going down it
becomes it's becoming more of a
necessity in the current
environment yeah so sequentially Al of
the business is definitely uh turned uh
you know better and turned Round the
Corner I should say but that said uh
most of our channels are doing well so
our stockist channel is doing well Urban
growth has come back we growing in urban
by around 80 kn% our rural growth which
is a super stock is being a barometer of
the performance is growing at around 25%
our e-commerce business is doing well
our institution business is still down
hka is still down is declining by around
30 odd per 25 30% which is Yet to Come
Back CSD is still declining and the CSD
hka both contribute to 33% last year uh
to the business contributions it's are
very significant to especially our food
business paror channel is not doing well
therefore skin care is under issue
modern trade is only growing by around
1.7% because of the future group issues
and as the future group issues with
Reliance get sorted out I think modern
trade will also come back then Reliance
is reconfiguring itself in the cash and
carry so Cash and Carry growth is also
only around 10 or% had Reliance been
doing well 50 stores Etc we would have
registered a growth of maybe 20% plus
there also so I think a lot of channels
and a lot of categories Like Home Care
skin care traditional categories hair
oils they are still not firing to their
potential so I think going forward they
should improve the channels and the
portfolios and healthc care business
which will come off a high base will
mute a little bit but in my view they
should balance each other uh going
forward
then one last question on the
international business uh any comments
on how that is tracking the non-middle
East recover recovered very strongly but
would there be some element of pipeline
in the non-middle East part of the
recovery and Middle East itself uh do
you still see the current headwinds
continue into the second half yeah so
Middle East in the current quarter in
the last quarter in which uh we saw the
results uh obviously faced macroeconomic
headwinds on account of crude oil prices
being low and therefore that having a
pressure on the economy and the
disposable income of the people a lot of
softs were drawn by the local emirati
and by local Saudis because they are the
true consumers of our business plus High
per capita consumers for daa brands are
expats actually moved out of that market
that had a you know issue with our
Middle Eastern business but as we go
along I think we come off a low base now
our Middle East business should recover
and the categories are also going back
back as now lockdowns have been removed
and people are getting used to the new
normal so Middle East business should be
back on recovery from uh current quarter
onwards and besides uh Middle East other
businesses uh Under Pressure are the
Subara business there which is Nigeria
and uh you would know the issues in
Nigeria and but because of the covid I
think Nigeria also gradually and slowly
should Trend back barring that all our
of international business are doing
reasonably well so I don't think there's
a problem Sark is already back
Bangladesh Nepal turkey America UK
Europe all the businesses are doing well
sub Sahara and Middle East are the only
two pressure points out of which Middle
East should recover and sub Sahara
should also recover in due course okay
thanks M that's it from my side all the
best yeah thank you Adam thank you thank
you lady ladies and gentlemen in order
to ensure that the management is able to
address questions from all participants
in this conference call please limit
your questions to one po participant for
any further questions you may come back
for a follow up the next question is
from the line of Tes sha from spark
Capital please go ahead uh hi hi Mo
congrats on a good set of numbers thank
you uh sir uh last September at the
analyst meet we had in in G uh you had
revealed the strategy of power brand and
and then Co happened and like many other
companies we also use tactically our
brand into many health and hygiene
platform and now we are talking about
changing the DNA of the company on npds
platform now if if you can just
elaborate are the two strategies of
power brand and then the new NPD
strategy are they mutually exclusive or
part of the same broader
construct right so these is they are not
mutually exclusive they're actually
subsumed in one it's actually Innovation
is a strategy we said then and we are
saying now it's Innovation across power
Brands only that we guys are doing like
real is our power brand so what you see
innovation in real we've launched a real
pet bottle we've launched a real fra we
are launching everything under real
homemade is a separate brand all
together so that is separate but
Innovations are happening in real
similarly in amla we've launched amla
aloe vera we launched HLA badam so we
are strengthening that only in hajola
we've launched a hajola Chula we are
launching a Haj Mula liula so we are
strengthening the Haj mola brand so in
hyas also we launching honey hyas hot
SHP and then there's a dber healthcare
brand under which you have a suraka te
coming up and you have a uh you know
eventually a MF coming up and and honey
variants coming up so the power Brands
and NPD they are not mutually exclusive
the power Brands will grow on back of
line extensions of these brands of brand
extensions of these Brands so it'll be
line extension brand extensions SQ
extensions of these power Brands and
therefore a brand which is 1,000 CR will
actually become a 2,000 CR and we will
get synergies of Investments also on
back of this so in my mind they are just
not um mutually exclusive they're
actually a similar strategy but what
happens is when you enter into a new
category which was opportunity presented
to us in covid like sanitization became
very big sanitization could not be
subsumed under our odonil brand or odos
brand or any other so therefore it
called for a creation of a new category
called dber sanitize which would cut
across the home hygiene and uh personal
and home hygiene that's why we created
that brand it's a opport Unity we can't
be slaves to one strategy that we save
the environment is so Dynamic so we have
to keep continuously changing or
tweaking our strategy that's what we
have done during these
times so just to follow up on that uh uh
daber brand is now been lent to from
pickle to Apple ciders so how should one
look at darber as a brand architecture
and how is this straty different from
what P attempted three years back and
then they saturated then their growth as
well
yeah so daber stands for uh Health
basically for us and that is the area
where daber will get extended apple
cider vinegar is also like a health
platform and this will only strengthen
the equity of dber as we get into it it
is a little different than pangali I
don't know how to compare it with
pangali or not to compare it with
pangali
um I don't think it's pangali it's our
execution Excellence which actually
makes is different from pangali and uh
to my mind pangali also did a very good
job out of
mizing ayurva I think uh their execution
and their funds management somewhere led
to the demise especially acquisition of
Ruchi soya now and therefore the cash
flow problems that the company is facing
and the quality issues uh which uh came
as a big hurdle to their growth
otherwise my mind the strategy wasn't
flawed it was okay that's my take as a
professional great that's all from my
side and happy to the whole
teamk you happy to you
too the next question is from the line
of prakash karia from an PMS please go
ahead moit thanks for the opportunity
and congrats on a good set of
results hello thank you thank you yeah I
had two
questions um excuse me this is the
operator Mr karia maybe request you to
use your handset please yeah yeah I
thank you yeah now am I
legible
yeah yeah uh you know can you help me
understand despite contribution from
health supplement if I look at gross
margins we are back on a year on
basis because of Ral cont for us at an
overall company level I would gu you
know Health Care a much higher cross
marking product for us you
know position prash we can't hear you
properly your voice is getting one
second let me yeah now is it better yeah
it's better now yeah yeah what I was
trying to understand is you know despite
increased contribution from you know the
healthcare port and especially chaan
gross margins have not actually you know
seen an increase so is it because rural
contribution from other products has
increased so that has a bit of offset
this gross margin because I guess rural
would be low lops and L margin am I
reading it
correctly no India gross margins have
actually gone up by 100 basis points
prash so that's a right analysis on
account of product mix so in favor of of
healthare it's actually the
international business wherein the gross
margins are lower because Middle East
business the high margin business did
not do well if you look at India
business gross margins have indeed have
gone up by 100 basis
points right right and on you know the
healthcare
segment on the OTC and the ethical side
which is largely you know chemist
Channel focus is there a lack of
distribution from I think the two black
kind of outlets which we had earlier and
you know can you give some sense on the
mix between the ethical and the OTC
portfolio in terms of
value right so as far as the
distribution is concerned prad we are
distributed like you rightly identified
that the distribution essentially with
chemist Outlets ethical portfolio is
distributed more in ayurvedic chemist
outlets and the OTC portfolio is more
available in the allopathic chemist
Outlets so ayic chemist Outlets are much
fewer in number as compared to
allopathic chemist Outlets ayic chemist
Outlets will be roughly around 100,000
is where we guys go to it is gone up
drastically and uh our OTC chemist
Outlets are in the range of around 275
which is going up from uh 245,000 to
275,000 and we are working on the same
so we are working on special Channel
programs across uh uh 4 5,000 chemist
outlets and trying to do visibility
there to drive demand even in OTC
chemist Outlets there a second part of
your question uh some value mix between
OTC and ethical portfolio can a
direction what was it historically what
is it
now OTC is a little larger and it is
growing at a faster pace and and uh I
think our presentation has the number so
you can check from yeah so ethical
business will be growing at around 26%
for us and ODC business is growing at
around 56% 55% uh on that business which
is almost I think double the size of our
ethical business and what we do is uh we
guys
cross-pollinate products from our
ethical business as they become scalable
we bring them on to OTC and make it
available in larger set of chemist
outlets and and that's how we grow
before it becomes available in grocery
also as it becomes a
FM so value sale wise
uh uh okay
right okay thank you all the
best thank you thank you the next
question is from the line of adya San
from Goldman Sachs please go
ahead hi uh good evening moan team and
thanks for time uh so
first
hello yeah yeah so just quickly on uh
any sense on how sales have been post
quarter particularly in October as we of
enter the festive season and and
secondly uh you launch several new
products on this Amazon big and and some
some of these other e-commerce events uh
how has the sort of response been to
those ad can we be a little away from
the can speak it's actually blaring we
are not able to understand what you
speaking all sure sure
this can you repeat please yeah yeah we
just wanted to get a sense on October
sales uh and also sales on some of these
Amazon big day and and events like that
where you launched some of your new
products yeah so I think the business is
uh I can't tell you the exact numbers
actually but the business is trending
okay as we enter into the festive season
so it's okay because uh this time Diwali
is later so therefore we did not stock
too much in the last quarter and the
stocking is happening now in this
quarter because Diwali has got postponed
and Amazon big days have been really
good for us and for e-commerce and as I
was mentioning in my con call address
also we've gained market shares across
our different categories on e-commerce
and we are gradually slowly looking at
increasing our market shares whether we
offline on e-commerce portals as well
that's why we are offering our a lot of
npds which are first time Ecom has
exclusively to either Amazon or to a big
basket so that we are able to get uh
traction from them so so far so good I
think October also things are only
improving uh from what we saw in the
second
quarter oh understand very clear and all
the best thank you very
much thank you the next question is from
the line of shirish peshi from Centrum
broking please go
ahead yeah hi good evening moit and
thanks for the opportunity and really
congratulations for the excellent
execution and solid volume growth my my
larger question is that in case of when
I look at last 10 quarter performance
the revenue growth and volume growth
doesn't fall and in between you gave
also the explanation that there is a
loading for the season which happens and
the retail sales happens in the
subsequent quarter now does that mean
that if the strong growth which we have
seen in quarter to uh we have more
challenges on our hand for the winter
portfolio also uh if the winter doesn't
pan out and what is your thought on the
core categories you sounded a bit
cautious saying that health supplement
or OTC may not repeat in the similar
range of
growth uh sorry Shish I did not get the
first part of your question can you
please repeat again I'm saying in the
past you have been guiding us that uh
there is there is always a different
skewness and pattern in terms of Revenue
and volume growth and I think uh last
year fourth quarter you explained that
uh there is a seasonality factor where
the loading in the trade happens uh uh
in the beginning and the subsequently
the retail sales happen in the next
quarter right so is that one read from
this quarter
number no not not not really SH now as I
told you the is got shifted got
postponed so the loading which used to
happen in the previous quarter has not
happened because the postpone of the
festive season so that we did not do
that loading we have done some loading
but the loading has been uh relatively
much lower despite the loading we have
corrected the pipelines by around 9 days
as I told you so we have corrected the
pipelines by 9 days so there is no
loading increasing the pipeline that the
secondary sales will happen later than
the primary sales so that is not the
case this time in the
quarter what I understand what you're
saying my my bigger question and I'm
wrestling in my mind saying that 50%
growth on a Yi in one quarter what has
changed if the industry Dynamics has
changed or the regional players like
Sandu B these people have not grown and
that's where we have got the market
share or is the whole Market is changing
I mean you explained partially saying
that the penetration level is gone up uh
by a percentage now with 1 percentage
increase our sales has gone up by 50%
and if the penetration goes another 5%
would we grow
5x absolutely if the penetration goes up
by 5% we will definitely go at 5x or 10x
for all you know so because our market
shares are only 60% today in chavan PR
so as the penetrations go up I think the
market leader is the one who actually
grows but that's not the reason why our
growth is there uh health supplement
growth of honey and Chan is only a one
part or I should say only a 10% part of
the picture of the growth that you are
actually witnessing if you see the
entire portfolio of D there is a growth
across portfolio so I would not say that
it's only health supplement it is OTC
portfolio which is grown it is ethical
portfolio uh which is actually grown
it's NPD which has come in it is even
the foods portfolio in domestic as I
told you has grown by around 8
.4% our Oral Care portfolio has grown by
24% our shampoo portfolio has grown by
18% so it's actually the GTM and The
Innovation and a lot of other strategy
pillars that we have put in place are
actually all firing and the execution
engine is doing uh fairly well for the
company so I think and plus to add it up
there's a Tailwind in healthcare which
obviously is the case uh which is
leading Chan prash and honey growth to
where they
are you're not worried about the
competition who has jumped in in Chan
prash and honey no no we are very
worried about it and I think we should
be very worried and not be very
complacent about it but there's little I
can do for it I think is only a brighter
side of this to look at that they will
improve the penetration levels in the
market and we will do whatever it takes
in the marketplace to protect our turf
yeah competition is a part of the
landscape and we can't do much we can't
do much about it so except that we will
keep charting our path of innovation and
improving on premiumization and creating
economy portfolio so that we are able to
utilize our uh rural infrastructure that
we put in place which is the entry
barrier for people to come in and nobody
can take away from D's equity and Legacy
and Heritage that we have in a
consumer's mind if a edible Oil Company
launches a chavan frash I don't know
whether a consumer wants to buy a oil in
a honey or oil in a Chan frash or How
does it go in the consumer mind that is
for you as consumers to choose
yeah well you said nicely my last
question on if I may squeeze in on Oral
Care uh you have done uh for many
quarters you have been beating industry
numbers what is working in your
experience and now you have got two more
ammunition which is uh last year you had
ayurvedic launch and then now you have
dakak and you have now clove which is
coming so could you able to uh tell us
what's changing in the market I mean
obviously non-white segment is picking
up faster as a natural base but then how
long do you think uh this trend or this
cycle will
last yeah so I think or category if you
see the natural and the herbal Subs
segment is the one which is growing as I
was telling you 8% versus 5% and that's
the case and this has become almost like
27 to 30% of the overall Market which
never used to be there so definitely
there's a tail Vin there a inclination
of the consumers to shift out from
whites and shift into herbal natural and
ayurvedic kind of platforms because they
are the value added forms and you know
if do I want to use a calcium carbonate
or do I want to use a calcium carbonate
plus a clove or a Mista and which is
much more effective when you do clinical
trials or when the efficacy happens
obviously you want to use a value added
and value added is here coming at a
cheaper price as compared to the calcium
carbonate so it's a cheaper better value
to the consumer which is what is working
here and is working for the entire
segment so dber is just trying to plug
the gaps that we are seeing geographical
gaps and also the benefit positioning
gaps and also the consumer gaps so
that's what we will be very soon wanting
to revamp our gel portfolio which we
launched as daa red gel which didn't do
very well but we are completely
revamping in next quarter you will see a
revamp of uh daa red gel happening and
we've got all these products somewhere I
think either the execution the
proposition uh did not work but then we
will keep uh improving like I keep
telling you progression is the way to go
and not Perfection we will keep
progressing and keep repositioning the
brand till the time they do well like
now l d Manan we had written it off that
it's a tooth powder category not growing
at all since we started investing we've
seen a uh ldm growth of around 30%
coming on manen so manen is back as
rural is growing and manen is growing
because rural is growing for us and that
is only enhancing the equity of
red in fact you you Tred to fely answer
my question on DDM uh the damin business
you purly grown because of your
Investments or uh is there the down
trining which is happening towards rural
consumers no it is really not down
trading it is a habit of the rural
consumer to use the mongen format
actually if you ask me if you look at
the price point if I look at the price
point of M is as much as the price point
of the toothpaste format uh being
different so the price points are uh
very similar so actually it could be a
little more expensive uh than uh our uh
toothpaste business so there's no
question of down trading it is a habit
that the consumer is used to using a mun
in rural areas and the urban consumer is
used to using a toothpaste and he can
upgrade and our margins are higher in
toothpast as compared to manin but that
said Mel is a habit and it's a very
effective format so therefore if you've
seen the recent advertising of daa red
we are uh promoting the use of powder as
a sprinkler on paste also on white paste
if consumer 50% of the population is
using a white paste we are telling them
to sprinkle our d l manen as a vitamin
or herbal supplement on top of their
pure carbonate to fch and make it
more effective so that's a new
communication that we've uh put on place
can sorry have people thank you and all
the best thank you very much thank you
participants we may request that to
please limit your questions to one per
participant for any further questions
you may come back for a
followup the next question is from the
line of Naman Jen from hm Securities
please go ahead uh yes hello everyone
and congratulations on the good set of
numbers uh I just wanted to ask you
about the supply chain and the
management that you guys are doing so I
just wanted to know how many new
suppliers have you added in this quarter
and what is your target going ahead to
reach new demographies and
geographies so supply chain Vis covid
times actually improved now so I think
there's no disturbance happening in our
supply chain only some localized
lockdowns uh happen and uh that's
besides that I think it's complete
streamlined operation that we have n we
have added a lot of third party vendors
uh in our supply chain base in terms of
vendors there must be around six seven
vendors that we may have added during
the course of the
quarter okay and one just one more
question uh what is the uh can you tell
me about the pipeline of the new
products that you're going to launch in
the coming quarters I mean how many are
there in the development
all right um you know as I told you
there will be there's no pipeline as
such first we have to establish the
products that we've already launched and
as we go along the percentage NPD will
be in the range of around 4 5% for us
going forward quarter after quarter I
can't give you the list of products and
the numbers we working on okay okay
thank you
you thank you the next question is from
the line of bat Kapoor from investtech
please go ahead yeah hi good evening
this is harit here uh so just two
questions one was on the hair oil side
uh if I look at the decline of 6% if you
could just give us a sense of what's
happened there uh is it a down trading
impact you're seeing uh in the category
or or something
else right har so in hair oils there are
two sub segments for us one is the
perfumed hair oil segment and the
coconut oil segment in coconut oil
segment which is growing we've gained
market share by around 10 basis points
in the perfume herol segment if you look
at if you discount the CSD and the
institutional business then our business
is almost flat in line with what the
category category of perfume declined by
minus one but our sales is almost flat
that said we've lost around 10 basis
points in uh perfumed hair oil segment
our flanker brands are doing well which
is saru amla has grown by 10 percentage
point so they are doing better so the
VIS is clearly illustrating that there's
a down trading happening uh that's why
you find a lot of Economy based
companies doing better than dla but our
flanker Brands continue to Surge well
there
so and and the second part was on
distribution so if you could just talk
about the first half uh you
know what the distribution expansion has
been
like so distribution expansion so we are
very much on course on the strategy to
in increasing our distribution so we've
gone up from last year of 1.2 million
we've gone up to around 1.3 million and
next year we'll go forward to around 1.4
million Outlets totally in urban and
rural in terms of number of villages we
lost a couple of villages because we we
could not serve them due to the covid
impact uh but by end of the year we will
go to our targeted number of 60,000
Villages and for next couple of years
we'll make a plan to take up the 60% to
around 80% that said we are now
appointing Village level entrepreneurs
and which is like Village Yodas what we
call them and uh we are appointing them
in some remote Villages where is where
there is no threshold level of business
coming in as in when we appoint them
they will become a inventory points and
there that's where we will try to do
some demand generation and gather
inventories as the business scales up we
will convert them into our sub stockage
so that's what we are doing also what we
have done and distribution is we have
split our HPC line into two parts HPC1
and hpc2 because there are 450 sqs are
carried by our home and personal care
guide to give a focus one we've made it
a hair care Centric Line and other we've
made it a Oral Care C line that's what
we are dividing we started our pilot
project in uh one or two Urban markets
and if successful then we've extend it
in other Urban markets
also that's very thanks and all the best
thank you very much thank
you the next question is from the line
of vi mahesar from Jeff please go
ahead
hi questions hi couple of questions one
comment about EMP spend you know you are
looking at Best in Class 12% number is
that what directionally you know what
you want to you know what you want to
achieve or let's say hit over the next
or in the medium term I I'm guessing
that you know there is a portfolio
difference also so that 12% number may
not be comparable as much but
incrementally is it what you are you
know what you are kind of planning to
invest at a broader portfolio
level yeah so that is the number that we
are working towards and we know that we
are at around 8% so we should gradually
slowly increase our advertising spending
looking at our Diversified portfolio I
think we've got too many amounts to feed
and too little resources so therefore we
have to get into uh higher degree of
investment for demand generation and our
products are also pre-seasonal so I
think we can uh do it so we have to get
the monies out from other avenues of
cost line items and that's what we are
working there for some RDI and all that
so therefore going forward in medium
term advertising spent will definitely
go up Vis last year uh I don't know by
what Horizon will I be able to achieve
12% but we will at least
e
e e
one broad question uh you know in the
context of the way higher growth that
you did for Q2
uh versus what you sort of projected and
alluded to uh you know to earlier and
your prognosis are what you have planned
for the months ahead uh how would you
align the the 5 to 6% growth objective
for the rest of the year that you had
been spelling out th
far yeah Richard we've not spelled out
the 5 to 6% objective for the balance of
the year we not say but that said I
can't give you any sort of a guidance on
the numbers going forward the situation
happens to be very volatile and
continuously in flux with covid second
wave kind of hitting us so one really
doesn't know as to how it will plan out
but uh just to let you know there is a
recovery and there is a recovery that we
see across all channels across all
categories especially depressed
categories like HPC and foods are also
seeing a recovery now coming back and we
are seeing growth as far as the health
supplements and health is concerned we
are now coming to a quarter of winters
which is of a high base so those
exponential
growth that we saw may not come in but
that said it can get compensated by the
HPC and Foods portfolio but I will not
be in a position to give you a guidance
because the situation is very volatile I
would also really not know as to how the
business will turn out to be but uh
we'll Target ourselves to deliver a
Healthy Growth
here okay all thank you wish you all the
best thank you thank you the next
question is from the line of aaz
motivala from nalis Partners please go
ahead good evening team thank you for
taking my question a little late in the
queue thank you um so my question to you
is on the uh uh on the point you alluded
to on uh in general the categories a
little bit of down trading and the value
segments of some of your businesses
taking off in particular hair oils and
uh and a couple the categories that we
called
out so so in terms of the contrast
ination that we've talked about in the
last few years would you be sort of
tweaking your strategy to launch some of
these as you said franker brands or
Warrior brands in in categories where
your core is very strong but uh you have
some customer down trading or or
competition nibbling to your market
share right the trend that we see uh is
definitely down Trading across our
segments so if you look at the food
business also so a one lit pack is gone
20000 ml has gone down to 150 ml 20
rupee pack to a 10 rupee pack so we've
launched LS or low unit price points or
accessible price points in toothpaste
also 20 rupee has gone down to 10 rupee
or 50 100 rupee has gone down to 10
rupee ha o also we have a 10 rupee price
point and 10 rupee and 20 rupee these
are cash Rings which are very important
for us to ride our rural infrastructure
and in rural business which is only
trending up at around 46% of US aliens
is in rural business it's important for
us to augment capacities in these
accessible price points and that's what
we have been doing although there'll be
little margin dilutive but that's okay
for us because it will provide us with
the scale and the heft on the top line
and that leverage our other line items
as we are able to scale up the business
in some larger Healthcare categories it
is not very easy to launch lups because
the ticket size required is big but we
are looking at improvisation of formats
which permit us to launch sashs or
tablets which are more at 10 rupee 5
rupee price points
yes and so just a follow up on the same
sort of down trading uh and and related
to to Modern trade uh are you getting
requests from specific uh for a modern
trade uh companies to have a unique
uniquely designed or uniquely packaged
Siz products uh for them to compete in
the marketplace um and how are you sort
of treating this uh versus a possibility
that they would be potentially launching
white label uh Brands any which ways as
a way of doing
business so so far we've not seen a
private label threat coming in
except for couple of categories like
home care which are more
commoditized uh rest of the places we
are not seeing a threat of white label
happening that said there's a channel
called Cason carry which is almost like
a Sate of wholesale there it's important
for the company to launch different skus
or different products so that it doesn't
undercut a regular GT so we are trying
to promote our non kvi is there to
ensure that undercutting doesn't happen
there so that is the need
developing for those segments of
business uh I really thank you very much
uh and it's been a very very open and uh
sort of transparent conversation that
you had all through this meeting and in
the last few so really appreciate that
thank you very much and happy diali to
the team and all the very best thank you
thank you very much happy diali to you
and as
well thank you the next question is from
the line of Kun from Jeff please go
ahead hi this is
again
hi I just missed you know on the ENT bit
so basically I was I just heard halfway
so you are talking about reaching 12
point of
time yeah correct so we want to inch up
to that level but it'll not be immediate
it'll be very slow and gradual process
of inching up as in when the PN
permits us like this time pnl permitted
us that's why you saw a growth of around
50% so we'll have to we can't erode our
bottom line for increasing our EMP so
we'll have to out right balance between
the operating margin and increasing our
spends also so it'll be a very prudent
approach in the way uh that we increase
principally we are aligned as a
philosophy to increase ourc and
Investments behind the brand and the
entire management committee is
completely on board but we'll have to
see the situation of the business so
that we don't erod profitability in the
B
game right and what will be roughly the
BT today in terms of as a percentage of
sales uh BTL uh for us will be in the
range of around 8 to
10% 8 10%
BT yeah so that will go down as ATL goes
up no what you see what is visible to
you uh VI is only ATL for you which is
around 8% the BTL which is there is
getting knocked off from the gross sales
as for the new
index I understand that part but I'm
just saying that you know as you push up
ATL the 8% BTL looks very high to me so
does that mean that you know as ATL goes
up BTL starts coming down yeah BTL
should BT actually is driven that's a
philosophy and principally sounds right
but BT is more driven by competitive
intensity in the marketplace if you got
a wholesaler and there were two
companies and one giving a 12% scheme
and if one doesn't want to give a 12%
then you lose out the wholesaler
investment to the competitor that's not
what you want to do so BPL is more
tactical in nature and ATL is more
longterm and more brand building in
nature so they can't replace each other
ideally in pnl we want to replace it
that's what every management does it but
I think the forces which work for each
one of them are very different one is a
demand building force and one is a
supply Force so they can't actually
replace each other you know what I'm
saying right sure sure the other
question M I have is on the sanitizer
scale which has gone down from 80 cres
to 12 cres for you in between first and
second quarter is there a pullback in
the industry uh revenues pool also you
think pull back in the industry Revenue
pool
basically right so there is a pull back
so because so many players are doing it
uh but I think consumer habits are
changing VI if you actually ask consumer
has got used to this kind of a disease
or infection now so the use of
sanitizers is actually gone down and the
use of liquid soaps and soaps have
actually gone up in the marketplace so
it was a initial thing to carry
sanitizer but now we don't see so much
of use of sanitizers that's what and I
think there's a industry pullback also
coupled with it because people have seen
the margins eroding here because so many
players have come in and the prices are
falling sure the reason I asked you
about sanitizer you know a you know drop
from 80 to 12 cres
does perspective you know given that you
know as customers or consumers become
more you know confident they can you
know the healthare may not necessarily
be in terms of quantum but there can be
you there can be a a decline in revenues
you know given as customers consumers
become used to the new world does not
really doesn't worry us so much because
the healthcare penetration in India so
low and there categories have been there
here for so many years it is not just uh
you know Johnny completely like a
sanitizer came in and it'll blow out
it's not like that seven CR and honey
have been there the part of our
tradition and they will never vanish VI
and therefore we're getting into more
and more better formats under the same
power brand strategy so that it doesn't
dissipate or uh uh you know have a same
thing like a sanitizers I don't think so
that's the case with our overall
Healthcare
portfolio sorry we need to move on can
go to the yeah last coule thank you very
much sure thank you vck yeah thank you
the next question is from the line of
Aken taker from Fidelity please go
ahead yeah hi just uh couple of
questions from my side one was to
understand the gross margin movement
this
quarter maybe just in Standalone so
you've seen 100 bips Improvement while
mix is improved quite a bit so just
trying to understand that does the 100
bips fairly you know reflect the mix
Improvement or was there some headwinds
you face uh this quarter which would
impactor
margin yeah so I think the margin
Improvement of 100 basis point that we
saw in the gross margin for India
Standalone is primarily because of the
fa favorable brand mix when I say the
favorable brand mix that means that the
sale of our jues were lower compared to
the high profitable products like
healthcare so therefore the brand mix
has added to the profitability and at
the same time there have been some
deflation uh deflationary impact also
seen uh because of crud Etc on the raw
material cost so that is also added and
there is a carryover of price increase
that has also given us a favorable
impact to some extent and as a result of
it our margins have improved by
100 okay uh the the next question was to
moit moit when you say that you know you
want to increase a uh you know let's to
double digit and and your construct like
you maintained over the last year year
and half is to maintain margins so so
where does the cost saving come from are
you looking at better gross margins in
the business or are you looking at
taking out
costs taking out cost I think there's a
lot of slabs uh in the organization the
other expenses which out for roughly
around 99.6% in the overall pnl and
there are other elements of cost ST cost
is there deing is there SNM is there so
there are lot of cost line items which
is where we can get the savings and it
can be plowed back into the this thing
that's why we've launched a Sami project
which is looking at end to endend Value
chain of the company and trying to take
out the cost elements and uh uh get the
savings from
there okay uh and the last question from
my side was you mentioned that your
secondary sales in the quarter was uh
higher than the primary sales uh any way
to quantify that or maybe just help us
understand how the Chan channnel
inventory was in June and and how does
it stand right now yeah so the channel
inventory uh last year this time was
around 24 days it has gone down to
around 15 days there's 9 days
Improvement in the channel inventory
across top stock stockist wholesale
across the board inventory levels we've
consciously brought down to a level of
around 15 days which is almost the best
in class now and we are trying to get
into CRS which is continuous
replenishment system with the keeping a
12 and 1 half day of inventory and
whatever the secondary is there that's
how the projection can happen uh for the
primary okay and this 15 days would have
been something similar in June quarter
as
well no it was substantially higher in
the we have corrected the inventory from
June to Now by around 2 to 3 days rest
be corrected in the June quarter sir
okay got it thank you so much thank you
thank you ladies and gentlemen we will
now close the question q and take the
last question from the line of Krishna
samam morti from mwal please go
ahead yeah uh thanks for taking my
questions and congratulations on a very
good performance uh my question is
regarding the something that is
highlighted in an report but did not
elaborate significantly which was on on
Project rise uh and the and the cluster
dat approach I can understand that uh
part of this is already uh being shown
in cies like conr can you elaborate a
bit and how significant will this be as
a part of your future
plan so I think rise is a complete uh
change in the way we guys are operating
rise while it means a regional insight
and speed for execution but it's also a
structural change in which we operate in
the organization we are trying to
empower our regional uh heads which are
east west north south and uh trying to
create an organization under them where
we'll identify Innovations and roll out
the Innovations also looking at state
level and region level pnls to uh
increase the business in different
regions so that is what we are trying to
do as a part of Rise so it's actually
pretty integral to the way we are
working and the organization is also
getting structured so that we are able
to empower the channel heads as more pnl
heads rather than only sales
heads okay but would something like a
Dak also be a part of the structure yes
absolutely because uh daa red is
actually very strong in South and weak
in North India in North pangali is
higher so it's basically a North
initiative that we've rolled out with
the
dakak and it's not launched in South
India it's not a national launch it's a
regional launch for us and there'll be
many more to come on this absolutely so
we are identifying products like for
example if you see in the product list
we've also got nambu K which has been
launched in South India this is also a
South India what we launched in North
India is called Cara what we launched in
South India is nambu K which is
basically a rise Initiative for us okay
and and
just does your Healthcare portfolio uh
have more of a potential here or do you
think that HPC also you can do more work
on this as a part of project price I
think across the board so we're trying
to identify insights across HPC HC and
Foods all the three pillars and uh also
empower the uh organization leads there
in different regions and also HPC HC and
Foods leads because we got all the three
segments in sales also so that's how we
are trying to create so across the board
understood uh thanks for congratulations
and all the best thank you very much
Krishna thank you ladies and gentlemen
that was the last question I now hand
the conference over to miss gagan alalia
for closing comments thank you sir thank
you uh all for your participation in
this conference call due to paity of
time if you've not been able to answer
all questions we can U answer them
offline please let us know a recording
and transcript of this call will be
available on our website soon thank you
and have a nice
evening thank you very much yeah thank
you very much ladies and gentlemen on
behalf of D India limited that concludes
this conference we thank you all for
joining us and you may now just connect
your lines